<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>InputBinding on Thomas Levesque .NET Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/inputbinding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in InputBinding on Thomas Levesque .NET Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 15:30:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/inputbinding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[VS2010] Binding support in InputBindings</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2009/10/26/vs2010-binding-support-in-inputbindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 15:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2009/10/26/vs2010-binding-support-in-inputbindings/</guid>
      <description>THE feature that was missing from WPF ! Visual Studio 2010 beta 2 has been released last week, and it brings to WPF a long awaited feature : support for bindings in InputBindings. As a reminder, the issue in previous releases was that the Command property of the InputBinding class wasn&amp;rsquo;t a DependencyProperty, so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible to bind it. Furthermore, InputBindings didn&amp;rsquo;t inherit the parent DataContext, which made it difficult to provide alternative implementations&amp;hellip; Until now, in order to bind the Command of a KeyBinding or MouseBinding to a property of the DataContext, we had to resort to clumsy workarounds&amp;hellip; I had eventually came up with an acceptable solution, described in this post, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really satisfied with it (it used reflection on private members, and had annoying limitations).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WPF] Using InputBindings with the MVVM pattern</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2009/03/17/wpf-using-inputbindings-with-the-mvvm-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2009 10:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2009/03/17/wpf-using-inputbindings-with-the-mvvm-pattern/</guid>
      <description>If you develop WPF applications according to the Model-View-ViewModel pattern, you may have faced this issue : in XAML, how to bind a key or mouse gesture to a ViewModel command ? The obvious and intuitive approach would be this one :
&amp;lt;UserControl.InputBindings&amp;gt; &amp;lt;KeyBinding Modifiers=&amp;#34;Control&amp;#34; Key=&amp;#34;E&amp;#34; Command=&amp;#34;{Binding EditCommand}&amp;#34;/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/UserControl.InputBindings&amp;gt; Unfortunately, this code doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, for two reasons :
 The Command property is not a dependency property, so you cannot assign it through binding InputBindings are not part of the logical or visual tree of the control, so they don&amp;rsquo;t inherit the DataContext  A solution would be to create the InputBindings in the code-behind, but in the MVVM pattern we usually prefer to avoid this&amp;hellip; I spent a long time looking for alternative solutions to do this in XAML, but most of them are quite complex and unintuitive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>