<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cosmos DB on Thomas Levesque .NET Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/cosmos-db/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cosmos DB on Thomas Levesque .NET Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/cosmos-db/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling type hierarchies in Cosmos DB (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2019/10/15/handling-type-hierarchies-in-cosmos-db-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2019/10/15/handling-type-hierarchies-in-cosmos-db-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second post in a series of 2:
 Handling type hierarchies in Cosmos DB (part 1) Handling type hierarchies in Cosmos DB (part 2) (this post)  In the previous post, I talked about the difficulty of handling type hierarchies in Cosmos DB, showed that the problem was actually with the JSON serializer, and proposed a solution using JSON.NET&amp;rsquo;s TypeNameHandling feature. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show another approach based on custom converters, and how to integrate the solution with the Cosmos DB .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling type hierarchies in Cosmos DB (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2019/10/14/handling-type-hierarchies-in-cosmos-db-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2019/10/14/handling-type-hierarchies-in-cosmos-db-part1/</guid>
      <description>This is the first post in a series of 2:
 Handling type hierarchies in Cosmos DB (part 1) (this post) Handling type hierarchies in Cosmos DB (part 2)  Azure Cosmos DB is Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s NoSQL cloud database. In Cosmos DB, you store JSON documents in containers. This makes it very easy to model data, because you don&amp;rsquo;t need to split complex objects into multiple tables and use joins like in relational databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using TypeScript to write Cosmos DB stored procedures with async/await</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2019/07/15/using-typescript-to-write-cosmos-db-stored-procedures-with-async-await/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2019/07/15/using-typescript-to-write-cosmos-db-stored-procedures-with-async-await/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: I am by no mean a TypeScript expert. In fact, I know very little about JS, npm, gulp, etc. So it&amp;rsquo;s entirely possible I said something really stupid in this article, or maybe I missed a much simpler way of doing things. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to let me know in the comments!
Azure Cosmos DB (formerly known as Azure Document DB) is a NoSQL, multi-model, globally-distributed database hosted in Azure. If you come from relational SQL databases, it&amp;rsquo;s a very different world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>