<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dependency injection on Thomas Levesque .NET Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/dependency-injection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dependency injection on Thomas Levesque .NET Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/dependency-injection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazily resolving services to fix circular dependencies in .NET Core</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2020/03/18/lazily-resolving-services-to-fix-circular-dependencies-in-net-core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2020/03/18/lazily-resolving-services-to-fix-circular-dependencies-in-net-core/</guid>
      <description>The problem with circular dependencies When building an application, good design dictates that you should avoid circular dependencies between your services. A circular dependency is when some components depend on each other, directly or indirectly, e.g. A depends on B which depends on C which depends on A:
It is generally agreed that this should be avoided; I won&amp;rsquo;t go into the details of the conceptual and theoretical reasons, because there are plenty of resources about it on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically inject fakes in test fixture with FakeItEasy</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2016/01/17/automatically-inject-fakes-in-test-fixture-with-fakeiteasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2016/01/17/automatically-inject-fakes-in-test-fixture-with-fakeiteasy/</guid>
      <description>Today I’d like to share a nice feature I discovered recently in FakeItEasy.
When you write unit tests for a class that takes dependencies, you typically need to create fake/mock dependencies and manually inject them into the SUT (System Under Test), or use a DI container to register the fake dependencies and construct the SUT. This is a bit tedious, and a few months ago I came up with an auto-mocking Unity extension to make it easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an auto-mocking container with Unity and FakeItEasy</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2015/06/14/create-an-auto-mocking-container-with-unity-and-fakeiteasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2015/06/14/create-an-auto-mocking-container-with-unity-and-fakeiteasy/</guid>
      <description>Unit testing can be tedious sometimes, especially when testing classes that have complex dependencies. Fortunately, some tools make it somewhat easier. I’ve been using FakeItEasy a lot recently; it’s a very easy to use mocking framework for .NET. It has a very lean and simple API based on generics and lambda expressions, and is a real pleasure to work with. It came as a breath of fresh air compared to the old RhinoMocks I had been using before.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>