<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gif on Thomas Levesque&#39;s .NET Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/gif/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gif on Thomas Levesque&#39;s .NET Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/gif/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A new library to display animated GIFs in XAML apps</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2015/01/17/a-new-library-to-display-animated-gifs-in-xaml-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2015/01/17/a-new-library-to-display-animated-gifs-in-xaml-apps/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, I wrote an article that showed how to display an animated GIF in WPF. The article included the full code, and was quite successful, since WPF had no built-in support for animated GIFs. Based on the issues reported in the comments, I made many edits to the code in the article. At some point I realized it was very impractical, so I published the code on CodePlex (it has now moved to GitHub) under the name WpfAnimatedGif, and started maintaining it there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WPF] Display an animated GIF image</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2011/03/27/wpf-display-an-animated-gif-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2011/03/27/wpf-display-an-animated-gif-image/</guid>
      <description>Note: The code in this article is out of date; the current code is hosted on GitHub. WPF is a great technology, but sometimes it seems to be missing some really basic features&amp;hellip; A frequently mentioned example is the lack of support for animated GIF images. Actually, the GIF format itself is supported by the imaging API, but the Image control only shows the first frame of the animation. Many solutions to this problem have been proposed on technical forums and blogs, usually variations of the following approaches:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>