<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>clipboard on Thomas Levesque&#39;s .NET Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/clipboard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in clipboard on Thomas Levesque&#39;s .NET Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/tags/clipboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>[WPF] Prevent the user from pasting an image in a RichTextBox</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2015/09/05/wpf-prevent-the-user-from-pasting-an-image-in-a-richtextbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2015/09/05/wpf-prevent-the-user-from-pasting-an-image-in-a-richtextbox/</guid>
      <description>WPF’s RichTextBox control is quite powerful, and very handy if you need to accept rich text input. However, one of its features can become an issue: the user can paste an image. Depending on what you intend to do with the text entered by the user, you might not want that.
When I googled for a way to prevent that, the only solutions I found suggested to intercept the Ctrl-V keystroke, and swallow the event if the clipboard contains an image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[WPF] Paste an image from the clipboard (bug in Clipboard.GetImage)</title>
      <link>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2009/02/05/wpf-paste-an-image-from-the-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog2.thomaslevesque.net/2009/02/05/wpf-paste-an-image-from-the-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Oops&amp;hellip; 2 months already since my previous (and first) post&amp;hellip; I really have to get on a more regular schedule ;)
If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried to use the Clipboard.GetImage method in WPF, you probably had an unpleasant surprise&amp;hellip; In fact, this method returns an InteropBitmap which, in some cases (most cases actually), can&amp;rsquo;t be displayed in an Image control : no exception is thrown, the image size is correct, but the image either appears empty or unrecognizable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>